Guide to the Marvin Chodorow Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Marvin Chodorow papers
1929-1993
1943-1974
SC0761
Chodorow, Marvin
12 Linear feet
Collection includes technical reports, articles, class files, memoranda, drafts and text for lectures, proposals and contracts, notes, correspondence, and minutes. Collection largely pertains to his research in linear accelerators, klystrons, and microwaves; professional activities; classes he taught at Stanford; and administrative duties at Stanford. There are also some materials pertaining to his classes as a student in the 1930s.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Chodorow received his B.A. in 1934 at the University of Buffalo, and his Ph.D., 1939, at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. He taught at Pennsylvania State College and College of the City of New York and worked with the Sperry Gyroscope Company (1943-47), before joining the faculty at Stanford in 1947. He served as Chair of the Department of Applied Physics from 1962-69 and Director of the Edward L. Ginzton Laboratory, 1959-78. He held a Fulbright Fellowship at Cambridge University, 1962-63, and was elected to the National Academy of Engineering, 1967, and the National Academy of Sciences, 1971.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes technical reports, articles, class files, memoranda, drafts and text for lectures, proposals and contracts, notes, correspondence, and minutes. Collection largely pertains to his research in linear accelerators, klystrons, and microwaves; professional activities; classes he taught at Stanford; and administrative duties at Stanford. There are also some materials pertaining to his classes as a student in the 1930s.
Access Terms
Chodorow, Marvin; Stanford University. Department of Physics.; Klystrons.; Linear accelerators.; Microwave tubes.; Physics.
Collection Contents
- Original Accession, Accession ARCH-2005-180
  - LEAP [Linear Electron Accelerator Proj ect] Table of Contents and Report 1 (Nov. 26, 1946) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - LEAP Report 2 (Dec. 18, 1946) and Report 3 (Jan. 4, 1947) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - LEAP Report 4 (Jan. 30, 1947) and Report 5 (Mar. 3,1947) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - LEAP Report 6 (Apr 2,1947) and Report 7 (Apr. 28,1947) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - LEAP Report 8 (June 16, 1947) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - LEAP Report 9 (July 31, 1947) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - LEAP Report 10 (Sept. 29, 1947) and Report 11 (Nov. 4, 1947) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - LEAP Report 12 (May 22,1948) and Report 13 (May 22 to Aug. 1,1948) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Microwave Lab Report 1 (1946) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Microwave Lab Report 2 Parts I-III (Jan.-June 1947) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Microwave Lab Report 2 Part IV (Jan.-June 1947) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Microwave Lab Report 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Microwave Lab Report 4 Parts I-IIL5 (1949) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Microwave Lab Report 4 Parts III.6-IIL9 (1949) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Physics 123 (Principles of Electricity), Winter 1934-1935: Text? (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Physics 123 (Principles of Electricity), Winter 1934-1935: Problems (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Physics 123 (Principles of Electricity), Spring 1934-1935: Text? (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Source Book Memo (June 1, 1960) and Introduction (Part I) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Source Book Part II (General Design) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Source Book Part III (Systems Design): A-F (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Source Book Part III (Systems Design): G-L (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Source Book Part IV (Operation) and Part V (Research Area Design) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Source Book Part VI (Shielding) and Part VII (Site and Buildings) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Source Book Part VIII (Organization), Part IX (Manpower), and Part X (Costs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Microwave Lab Report for 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Microwave Lab Report 5 (Jan-Mar 1950) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Microwave Lab Report 6 (Apr-June 1950) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Microwave Lab Report 7 (July-Sept 1950) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Microwave Lab Report 8 (Oct-Dec 1950) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Microwave Lab Report 9 (Jan-June 1951) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - MP166-186 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - MP187-206 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Input Impedance of Klystron Resonators, 9/28 /44 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Velocity Spectrograph Measurements of Beam Loading, 10/23 /44 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Experimental Determination of Impedance Functions by the Use of an Electrolytic Tank, 9/1 /44 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - On Stagger-tuned Low-pass Amplifiers, 9/14/44 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stagger-Tuned Amplifiers, 10/1 /44 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - On Maximum Gain-Bandwidth Product in Amplifiers, 11128/44 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Index for Early Stanford Reports (1931-1953) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Report on a Continuous Wave Airplane Location System by W. W. Hansen (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - A 200,000 Volt X-Ray Tube, by W. W. Hansen, Dec. 1931 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Peacetime Applications of Microwaves, by W. W. Hansen (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - High Current-Density Electron Beam Project, by Field/Helm/Spangenberg, Oct. 15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Reports on Klystron Oscillators, by G. E. Hackley, Oct. 1942-Nov. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Air Traffic Control Antenna, by W. W. Hansen, May 20, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Resonator Design for a High Voltage Klystron, by A. E. Harrison, Aug. 20, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Results of Attempts to Make a Conducting Film on Glass Using Stannous Chloride" by J. Mann (Nov. 7, 1947) and "High Power Pulsed Klystrons: Their Lives and Our Hard Times" by I. R. Neilsen (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Microwave Local Oscillator Project reports (May 1, 1946- June 30, 1947) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - An Electrical Network for the Study of Electromagnetic Fields by Spangenberg and Walters (May 15, 1947) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Production of Flash Radiographs by Means of the Linear Electron Accelerator by W. R. Kennedy, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Electron Trajectories in Reflex Klystrons in the Presence of Space Charge by V. B. Westburg, (April 26, 1948) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Spectrum Analyzer by A. B. Vane, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Short-lived Isomers ofTa " and "Experimental Physics Research in the Accelerator Project" by W. C. Barber (Jan 23, 1950) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Energy-Angle Distribution of Thin Target Bremsstrahlung" by L. I. Schiff (July 15,1951) and "Electron-Tube Research at Stanford" by C. Susskind (1953) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Development of a Helix-Type Backward-Wave Oscillator for the 10- to 20-kMc/s Range" (Apr. I-June 30, 1953) and (July I-Sept. 30, 1953) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 1 (Nov. 13, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 2 (Dec. 20, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 3 (Feb. 8, 1962) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 4 (Nov. 13, 1961) and 5 (Nov. 8, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 6 (Jan. 15, 1962) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 7 (Feb. 8, 1962) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 8 (Dec. 20, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 9 (Feb. 8, 1962) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 10 (Dec. 20, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 11 (Feb. 8, 1962) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 12 (Nov. 13, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 13 (Nov. 13, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 14 (Nov. 13,1961) (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 15 (Nov. 13, 1961) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 16 (Nov. 24,1961) (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 17 (Jan. 15, 1962) and 18 (Feb. 8, 1962) (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 19 (Dec. 20, 1961) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 20 (Jan. 26, 1962) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Translations of Russian Plasma Articles 21 (Feb. 8, 1962) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 30 copies of gear drawing on tracing paper (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Monte Carlo Calculation of Noise Near the Potential Minimum of a High Frequency Diode (Mar. 5, 1956) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letter from National Academy of Sciences regarding Formal Ballot (Dec. 20, 1984) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Quantum Electronics Research (June 1974) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Electromagnetic Waves (July, 1960) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Electromagnetic Techniques Department Computer Programs for Analysis and Design of Electric and Magnetic Devices (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Black and white photo: Men fishing in a river (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Folder labeled TAC (July 12, 1962) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Folder labeled "For M. Chodorow." Contains material regarding Academy of Arts and Sciences, meeting on the Idea of Progress. 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Folder "For M. Chodorow." Contains technical and photo slides (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Folder "Dr. Marvin Chodorow from Al Scott" Technical slides. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 2 Copies of Administrative Supplement for July 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Criteria for Growing Waves, Evanescent Waves and Absolute Instabilities, Revised Aug. 1972. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fiber-optic Gravitational-wave Sensors (May 8, 1980) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Technical Notes: Turbomolecular Pumps (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - p. 265-278 ofIEEE Transaction on Sonics and Ultrasonics (July 1979) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fiber Ring Laser Gyro Amplifier (Nov. 27,1978) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 8 copies of AFTER Program Special Topics Course 397A (Oct. 7-Dec. 2, 1981) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 2 copies of Instrumentation for Acoustical Discrimination of Biological Cells 1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 4 copies of Final Scientific Report on Instrumentation for Acoustical Discrimination of Biological Cells (Dec. 1977) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Quarterly Progress Report on Instrumentation for Acoustical. .. (Nov. 1974) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Class Materials for Microwave Electronics: EE 326C/ AP 256, Spring quarter 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Theorie Fondamentale de l'Electronique en Hyperfrequences (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Class Material for AP Courses- Mainly problem sets (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 2 copies of Stanford Daily from Apr 1, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Microwave Research Quarterly Status Report (June 1963) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Multimegawatt Broadband Microwave Tubes (May 1963) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Litton Presentation (Nov. 3, 1993) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Progress Report No.5 on Microwave Research (Jan-Mar. 1950) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 8 diagrams wrapped in another larger one (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Draft: The RF Solution of the space charge limited, spherical diode. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Memos on Large Signal Klystron Theory (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Analysis of a Proposal for a non-scanning Radio Frequency Spectrum Analyzer (Sept. 1, 1947) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Research and Development Board" Mainly regards Millimeter Wave Generation (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - A Simple Graphical Method for Determining the Settings of a Triple Stub Tuner (Nov. 1950) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Progress Report No.6 on Microwave Research Apr-June 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Proposed talk at I.R.E. National Convention NYC, Mar. 6, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Review from June 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bunching Theory for Three Resonator Velocity Modulation Systems (July 18, 1944) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Some Notes on Indicators for Non-Scanning Radio Receivers (Sept. 6, 1946) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Doppler Radar (Aug. 2, 1946) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Theory of Linear Electron Accelerators (May, 1951) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - High-Power Applications of the Connected-ring Structure in Traveling- Wave Tubes (Dec. 1958). [included inside: "Small Signal Ballistic Analysis" and yellow legal papers] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Influence of Electron Beam Behavior on Klystron Efficiency (Oct. 1958) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Materials for meeting of National Academy of Engineering, March 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Revue Technique de la Compagnie Francaise (April 1956) [included inside: "A Mathematical Theory of Communication" (July 1948) and "Optical Maser Oscillators and Noise" (Jan. 1964)] (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - A Description of the Bell Laboratories Scanned Acoustic Microscope (Nov. 1982) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Pulse Stretching in a Q-Switched Nd:Yag Laser (Nov. 1979) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Administrative Supplement for August 1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Acoustic Microscopy at Cryogenic Temperatures Status Report (Jan 1979) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Nonlinear Generation of Sound in the Scanning Acoustic Microscope Final Report for 7/15/1977-2/28/ 1981 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - IEEE Transactions on Sonics and Ultrasonics (Mar 1985) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - International Convention on Microwave Valves (May 19-23, 1958) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Errata for M. L. Report No. 149 (July 16, 1952) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Choice of Wavelengths and Characteristic Parameters in the Design of Linear Electron Accelerators (Sept. 1955) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - A Study of Multi-Bev Linear Electron Accelerators (June 1954) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Progress Report for 1946 on Microwave and Klystron Research (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Acousto-Optic Interactions: Final Report (July 1976) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - URSI Meetings Minutes- Committee VII (Oct. 8, 1957) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - New Approaches to Optical Systems for Inertial Rotation Sensing (Dec. 1981) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Proposal on Research on New Approaches to Optical Systems for Intertial (sp) Rotation Sensing (Sept. 21,1981) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Integral Delay Lines Research Proposal (May 1967) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Summary of Present Applied Microwave Acoustic Programs (Sept. 20, 1966) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - New Approaches to Optical Systems for Inertial Rotation Sensing (Sept. 1980) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Theorie Fondamentale de l'Electronique en Hyperfrequences (second copy) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Budgets-Financing for Microwave Lab 1962-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Engineering Nominations for Membership (1973- 1974) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - ML Statistics 1957-1964 by Al Braun (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Theory of Noise from the Reflex Oscillator (Jan. 10, 1946) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - A New Directional Coupler for Waveguides (July 18,1946) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Black and White Photo "Figure 9 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Waveguide Circuit Theory: Coupling of Waveguides by Small Apertures (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - A New Method of Estimating Preoscillation Noise in a Pulsed Oscillator (Magnetron) (Aug. 30, 1950) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nuclear Magnetism (Jan. 1954) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Doppler Radar Systems (Oct. 15,1943) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Theory of Disk-loaded Waveguides (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Summary of Recent Work on the Centipede High-Power Traveling-Wave Tube and the Electron Stick (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Relation Between Nodal Positions and Standing Wave Ratio in a Composite Transmission System (June 5, 1943) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Diffraction Problems of Microwave Optics (Aug. 12, 1954) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 3 copies of Summary of United States Work on Interaction Between Plasmas and Electromagnetic Fields 1957-1960 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 5 copies of Summary of United States Work on Low-Noise Beam-Type Microwave Tubes Sept. 1957 -Sept. 1960 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Electron Ballistics in High-Frequency Fields (1945), drawings inside (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Theory of Reflex Oscillators (19507) also many figures (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Wavebook Handguide Supplement (Jan. 23, 1945) [included inside: Space Charge Waves in Inhomogeneous Electron Beams] (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 2 copies Denshi Tokyo March 1959, signatures on back (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 5 copies of graph paper clipped to cardboard (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Talks (1959) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Chodorow Technical Memos 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Task 23 Memos 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hague Tube Conference? Aug. 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Chodorow (1955-1956) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Beam Loading Material Dec. 17, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Collins Harmonic Analysis Grids and Instructions (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - AGET Survey 1957 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - High Power X-Band Generator (Jan. 25, 1963) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Microwave Research Quarterly Status Report No. 12 (Feb. 1962) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Science Writers' Symposium Talk (July 30 and 31, 1959) and Notes (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Rough drafts of speech about research in a Microwave Lab (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Rand Symposium Talk and "High-Power Traveling-Wave Tubes (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Journal Club Talk (Feb. 20, 1957) and AGET Talk (Dec. 12 and 13 1956) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Talk for PGED (Oct. 21, 1957) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - U of Michigan Talk (Feb. 4, 1958) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Talk for TAC Meeting (March 1958) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Talk for Osaka, 2 Drafts (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Physics 213 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Chodorow 's birth certificate (copy) (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Plasma Research Institute letters (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and text for talk on microwave tubes, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Miscellany: letter about civilian access to atomic power, 1946, calculations and notes, classified material authorization, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Diagrams and manuscript of a Microwave Impedance Bridge (June 14, 1948) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Memo and list of French Patent applications (Aug. 8, 1946) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Summaries of French Patents and applications (Sept. 9, 1946) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Theory of Reflex Oscillators Part I (Feb. 28,1947) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - A Contribution to the Mathematical Theory of Big Game Hunting (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Grant of Consent for Marvin Chodorow (Mar. 18, 1949) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Survey of Possible Experiments with Linear Electron Accelerators (Nov. 1949) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Elements of Reflex Klystron Theory (Feb. 3, 1943), incl. Loose leaf calculations and graph paper (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The Input Impedance of Klystron Resonators (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - The Upper Atmosphere Table of Contents (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Notes on the Reflex Oscillator (May 3, 1945) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - On the Focusing of High-Current Electron Beams (Feb. 1954) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - General Studies in High Power Microwave Concepts (Mar. 1962) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Final Quarterly Status Report (No.8) Investigation of the Microwave Properties of Plasmas (Feb. 1961) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Lithium Niobate Story (Feb. 1971) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Campus Report (May 29, 1974); mentioned in article "Faculty Senate acts on CPS" (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Classification A Report Index (typescript) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Graphs (unlabelled) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Study of some Microwave Applications of Paramagnetic Resonance (Jan. 29, 1952) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Blueprints for patent (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Rieke Diagram-Reflex Tubes, notes (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - United Air Lines 100,000 Club (Feb. 26, 1960) -letter and his mileage calculations (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Assembly of the International Scientific Radio Union (Aug. 23-Sept. 2, 1954) (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Articles by Richard Pantell, sent from Rudi Kompfner, 1968-77 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Centipede structure - contains note about folded waveguide circuits (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Discussion of Lateral Instabilities (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Large Signal Effects (photocopy of notes) (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Head-Tail Effect II: From a Resistive-Wall Wake, Matthew Sands (Apr. 24, 1969) (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - The Head-Tail Effect: An Instability Mechanism in Storage Rings, Matthew Sands (Mar. 28, 1969) - only first page (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - High-Power Traveling-Wave Tubes Rough Draft (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - National Academy of Engineering Project Committee-Miscellaneous Reports (1969-1971) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Engineering Project Committee-Miscellaneous Proposals (1969-1972) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Engineering Project Committee-Meetings 1968, 1969, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Oblique incidence reflection acoustic imaging, Yeack and Chodorow, Sept. 1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Lectures of Dr. W. W. Hansen (Given at MIT 1941-44). Volume 4 of 4 volumes (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Physics 211-212-213-214 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Academic Council 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Applied Electronics Laboratory 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Paul Fihe 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Theory of Bunching 1943 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Space Charge Effects (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Klystron Program Redesign 23 Special 1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - M. Chodorow Report #1 (handwritten) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - MTT Computation Book, Research, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Calif. Research & Development Company-consulting, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Calif. Research & Development Company- extension of agreement, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - CSF Report (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Beam Loading in Klystrons (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Theory of the Double Catcher, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Optimal Wavelength for Long Range C. W. Radar Systems, May 1, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - LEAP Navy Contract N6-ori-l06, Task IV, July 31,1947 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Outline for a Theory of the Space Charge in an Oscillating Magnetron, July 1, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Further Comments on the Periodic Coupling of Two Propagating Structures (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence wi Gordon Kent, Oct. 19, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence M. Chodorow- Paris, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous 1947-1956 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Theory of Magnetron Operation, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (microwave impedance?) (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Notes (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Theory of Reflex Oscillators and Security of Stanford Lab, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Introduction to Microwaves, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Summary of Methods of Calculation of Ez for Cylindrical and Slot Gaps, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Klystron Curves (handwritten notes) (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - 1st Quarterly Report on H. P. Klystron 1947? (handwritten) (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Microwave Research (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Amplification of Cyclotron Waves- Memo, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Physics 53, Electricity, Spring 1956 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Physics Department, 1958-1961 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Microwave Circuits II (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - High Power Microwave Tubes 1956 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Tube Design Notes (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - LEAP Project, Task IV, Reports 1,4-8, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Contrabound X -band TWT (graphs and charts) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence on Linear Accelerators and Proof, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Chodorow Consultant Agreements, etc. 1952-1960 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - The Periodically-Loaded Traveling-Wave Klystron Theoretical Analysis of Performance, P.A. Lindsay, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Study of a Waveguide-TWT Coupled System by Three-Coupled-Mode Theory, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Suppressing Oscillations in the High-Power Centipede TWT 1961 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Patents 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Cost Equation and Diagrams 1958 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Reports 1957 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Students 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Invention Disclosures, 1953-1958 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Stub Supported Data (Graphs) (Box 12, Folder 18)